We already did one input parameter together.
入力パラメータがひとつの場合 はすでに説明しました
This was the code for the calculatePrice method that was already included in
それはインストラクターメモに 含まれている
the instructor notes.
calculatePriceメソッドの コードでしたね
Now let's do the case of two input parameters.
では入力パラメータが 2つの場合を見ていきましょう
In the submitOrder method, we want to call calculatePrice (quantity, 10).
submitOrderメソッド内に calculatePrice (quantity, 10)を呼び出します
Where 10 represents $10 per cup of coffee.
ここで10は コーヒー1杯が 10ドルであることを意味します
So let's first make this change.
まず これを変更しましょう
In the submitOrder method I'm going to call calculatePrice(quantity, 10).
submitOrderメソッド内に calculatePrice (quantity, 10)を呼び出します
I'm passing in two arguments to this method.
このメソッドに引数を2つ 渡します
There's an error because it doesn't match the method signature here.
メソッドのシグネチャーと合致せず エラーになるので
And I'm about to update that.
それを更新します
Inside the parentheses I'm going to add a comma.
カッコの中に カンマを追加し
And then type in int price
次いでint priceと 入力します
because we're passing in price as the second input and that's an integer.
価格を2つめのインプットの整数 として渡すからです
Immediately it says that there's an error because
すると即座に エラーが出ます
it doesn't match the method signature here which only has one input parameter.
入力パラメータがひとつしかない このメソッドシグネチャーと合わないからです
I'm going to change it so that it has a second input parameter.
入力パラメータを2つに 変更します
So inside this opening and
このカッコの中に
closing parenthesis, I'm going to add a second parameter.
２つ目のパラメーターを 追加します
Since this is the price per cup of coffee, I'm going to call it
コーヒー1杯あたりの価格なので これを
price per cup, and it's a number, so I'm going to say that the data type is int.
pricePerCupとしましょう 数字なのでデータ型はintです
The name of the parameter type can be anything you want.
パラメータの型名は 好きなものでよいです
It should be descriptive to the information that it's holding.
そこに入る情報の性質を 表すものにします
Whereas the data type needs to be a specific java data type.
データ型は 特定のjavaデータ型 でなければいけません
So int string and other ones that we haven't learned yet.
intストリングや その他 まだご説明していないものです
I also updated the java doc to describe this second imput parameter.
javadocを更新して ２つの入力パラメータを記述しました
When I look inside this method, we're taking quantity and
このメソッドの中を見てみると quantityがあり
multiplying it by 5 for $5 for a cup of coffee.
それに5をかけて コーヒー1杯あたり5ドルになります
But now the price per cup has changed to a variable.
コーヒー 1杯の価格は 変数に変更されましたので
So let's use price per cup instead of hard coding to value 5.
5という値の代わりに pricePerCupを使いましょう
Now the total price of the order is going to be quantity
これで注文合計額は quantity x pricePerCup
times price per cup.
になります
If you think back to the template analogy that I was talking about
先ほどご説明したテンプレートの話を 思い出してください
earlier, now quantity and price per cup are swappable for
今度は 数量と1杯あたりの価格は
different values because their input parameters.
入力パラメータのおかげで 異なる数値と交換することができます
You could call calculate price with a different quantity and
culculatePriceを 異なる数量と異なる価格で
a different price per cup and this computation would still work.
呼び出してもこの計算は うまくいきます
Now let's do the case of zero input parameters.
では入力パラメータが ゼロの場合を見てみましょう
In the submit order method,
submitOrderメソッド内で
we should call calculate price with empty parenthesis.
カッコ内が空の calculatePriceを呼び出します
In the submit order method, when I call calculate price,
submitOrderメソッド内に calculatePriceを呼び出したら
I'm going to remove the arguments.
引数を削除します
Now we don't pass any inputs into this method.
このメソッド内に 入力を何も渡さないと
There's a red underline immediately because there's a mismatch with
メソッドシグネチャーと合わないので 赤い下線が表示されます
the methods signature, so I'm going to go ahead and
そのまま進み
erase all these input parameters.
これらの入力パラメータを すべて消します
This is also complaining about an error because these parameters don't exist so
これらのパラメータが存在しないので まだ文句を言っていますね
I can go ahead and delete this.
そこでこれも消します* pricePerCupが解決できない メッセージが出ます
Now we get an error saying that it can't resolve the symbol price per cup.
もう入力変数ではないので ハードコードの価格に戻します
the hard coded price value which is $5 or you could pick any other price.
5ドルでもよいですし 好きな数字を選べます
The computer doesn't complain about quantity because it's actually
コンピューターは数量については 文句を言いません
a global variable, and
なぜならquantityはグローバル変数で
you can reference this quantity variable from any method in the main activity.
メインアクティビティの どのメソッドからでも参照できるからです
Sorry. I should have picked a name other than
すみません 入力パラメータには
quantity for the input parameter.
数量以外の名前を 選ぶべきでした
But you get the idea, without any input parameters,
けれどもご理解いただけましたね 入力パラメータがないと
you could only refer to global variables.
グローバル変数しか 参照できません
You can use hard-coded values or if you create local variables here,
ハードコードの数値または ローカル変数をここで作成すれば
you can refer to those.
それらを参照することもできます